Kimberly Palmer

Camarillo, CAI 408-234-8037 | Kimberly.L.Palmer@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Blog

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer with a rich blend of Python, Flask, React, and JavaScript programming skills, I bring over 15 years of leadership in project and program management. My expertise lies in technical proficiency with strong collaboration and problem-solving skills. Known for driving growth and fostering key relationships, I excel in using technology to enhance and meet complex organizational goals. My passion lies in applying this unique combination of tech skills and experience to innovate and lead in challenging software engineering roles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python with Flask, SQL, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Canva, Figma, WordPress, Elementor

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Motivational-Engine - Github | Demo

Motivational Engine is a unique web application designed to boost productivity and uplift spirits through the power of positive affirmations. This project is built using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

• Using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS created a motivational task list website

Slay The Day - Github

A simple personal calendar application

Using React, HTML and CSS, created a simple personal calendar app

Library Management - Github

Library Management System is a Python CLI application designed to manage a library's books, members, and borrowing records. It uses SQLAlchemy for database operations and provides a user-friendly interface to interact with the library's data

created python CLI + ORM project

What's For Dinner - Github

What's for Dinner is a full-stack web application designed to help track recipes. Future releases will have a recipe randomizer, meal planner and shopping list generator for planning meals a week at a time. I developed this application using React and Flask.

created React + Flask project

EXPERIENCE

Irwin Naturals Emergence

Los Angeles, CA

Senior Program Manager

July 2022 - September 2023

- Strategic Analytics Implementation: Spearheaded the design and execution of advanced system dashboards using Google and Microsoft tools, significantly enhancing the tracking of key departmental metrics. This strategic initiative resulted in a remarkable 50% increase in patient engagement and a 35% improvement in service efficiency.
- Leadership & Team Management: Led a hybrid team of 8 professionals in the strategic introduction of innovative
 tools and procedures for both new and existing operational sites, ensuring seamless integration and operational
 excellence.

American Society of Ketamine Physicians

Ventura, CA

Director of Operations

02/2019 - 03/2022

• Leadership, Operational Excellence & Revenue Growth: Spearheaded the organization and comprehensive management of the annual conference, attracting over 400 attendees by adeptly applying project management methodologies. Additionally, implemented a strategic membership renewal program, both of which collectively propelled organizational revenues by an impressive 250%. This dual-strategy approach not only expanded our audience but also increased our membership engagement, demonstrating a direct correlation between innovative program implementation and significant revenue growth.

CCI, Inc

Los Angeles, CA

Senior Program Manager

January 2010 - February 2022

• **C-Suite Executive Engagement:** Cultivated strategic relationships with C-suite executives in the healthcare sector, enhancing corporate partnerships and strategic alliances.

- Event Management & Team Development: Oversaw all aspects of event planning and execution, leading internal teams towards improved service metrics. Instituted comprehensive training protocols for new staff, fostering professional growth and operational efficiency.
- **Financial Stewardship:** Managed and reported on project budgets ranging from \$40,000 to \$120,000, ensuring meticulous tracking of expenditures. Optimized budget allocations for maximum efficiency and impact, and provided detailed financial forecasts to stakeholders, facilitating informed strategic decisions.

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program

Camarilol, CA

10/2023 - 02/2024

Touro University WorldwideBS in Business Administration and Management

San Lorenzo, CA 08/2018